<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>tlebryk.github.io/theo-in-hk/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>A smorgasbord of clickbate headlines, uninformed thoughts about Hong Kong, and the thing the internet most needs: another food blog.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>What People are Saying about the Protests Part I</title>
	  <link>/theo-in-hk//the-businessman-and-fisherman</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2019-10-15T18:18:00+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/theo-in-hk//the-businessman-and-fisherman</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This is the first part in an ongoing series of posts excerpting different perspectives I encounter on the protests in Hong Kong. This is in no way a representative sample of Hong Kong, nor should these people be thought to speak for everyone in their demographic. However, hopefully this gives some color, and alternative perspectives, to what the media is publishing about the protests.</p>

<!-- wp:heading {"level":5} -->
<h5>On the current state of the protests</h5>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Under no conception of political legitimacy anymore is the Hong Kong government legitimate anymore…even under Confucian notions of the mandate of heaven, the government has stopped serving the interests of the people. That doesn’t mean we can have vigilante justice, but we need to think a lot on this question of how the government can regain legitimacy. </p><cite>A Hong Kong academic</cite></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":5} -->
<h5>On divides within Hong Kong </h5>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p> <br /> <br /> These protests are literally tearing families apart. They are divided along generational lines: a lot of the old folk don't understand why the young people are doing what they are doing right now. There are stories of people moving out of <a href="https://www.hongkongfp.com/2019/09/17/war-dinner-table-hong-kong-families-divided-protests/">home</a> or videos of fights within families that are going viral.  </p><cite> A Hong Kong academic</cite></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":5} -->
<h5>A conspiracy theory </h5>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>These protesters are pawns of the political game in Beijing. In Beijing, there are two factions: the current ruling faction with Xi Jinping and the old faction left over from [former president] Hu Jintao. There's a lot of money from mainland China sitting in Hong Kong. Xi wants to draw that money back - thus the extradition bill and attempt to stir chaos in Hong Kong so that there is a reason for the government to go in and take back that money. The other faction doesn't want their money removed from Hong Kong and they've maneuvered to keep Hong Kong as a special administrative zone for now. The protesters have legitimate demands, but it's actually all about Beijing.  </p><cite> A man from mainland China working in Hong Kong</cite></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Quick Commentary: Definitely take this one with some skepticism, but I thought it was worth including because it raises the interesting point that we have no feel for any factions or divisions in strategy within the upper echelons of the Chinese government. This point is true in general, but especially on the issue of Hong Kong,</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":5} -->
<h5>On the future of Hong Kong</h5>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Even if we have these protests, I still don't know about the future of Hong Kong. In maybe 20 years the country could be 50% mainland Chinese [said hyperbolically]. There are already elementary schools in the New Territories [the area closest to mainland China] that are taught in Mandarin. If these people don't know the freedom we have or anything about democracy, we will become like China.  I don't understand why you would escape a dictatorship and then come and bring it here. </p><cite>A Hong Kong young professional</cite></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
