<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>tlebryk.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>A smorgasbord of psuedo-scientific observations about Hong Kong, clickbate headlines, and the thing the internet most needs: another food blog.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Tomato Egg Stirfry (番茄炒蛋)</title>
	  <link>//Tomato-Egg-Stirfry</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-02-28T05:18:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//Tomato-Egg-Stirfry</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>There are tons of versions of this classic Hong Kong comfort food but every one I’ve found does this recipe the proper way. That is: scramble the eggs, remove, stir fry tomatoes, and then add eggs back in at the end.
No one (by that I mean sample size of four Hong Kongers I cook with) actually cares enough to go through the work of scrambling first then cleaning the pan.</p>

<p>This post gives you the “lazy” way of stir-frying the tomatoes, then cooking the eggs in the tomato juice. Honestly, I feel like very little is lost by not doing two separate processes. In fact, this way is harder to botch. If you do them separate, you have to time things right so as to not overcook and dry out the eggs. This one, you kinda just eye-ball until you no longer have raw eggs in your tomato juice. Lastly, the legit way comes out more like scrambled eggs with tomato juice on top. If you prefer runny eggs, this way comes out more like tomatoes with eggs floating around. Upon writing that, I realize that sounds pretty unappetizing, but you actually get the eggs mixed thoroughly with the juice, meaning every egg bite is sweet.</p>

<p>Ingredients</p>
<ul>
  <li>5 eggs</li>
  <li>3 tomatoes</li>
  <li>~ 2 tablespoons Sugar</li>
  <li>~1 tablespoon of Salt</li>
  <li>Optional add ins: scallions, ketchup, Pepper/chili flakes</li>
</ul>

<p>Serves: however many people can eat 5 eggs and three tomotoes….so like 4 normal people for breakfast?</p>

<p>Instructions</p>
<ol>
  <li>Whip the eggs like scrambled eggs To be fluffier, add water to the mix.</li>
  <li>Cut tomatoes into thin wedges (~1/8s).
   a. The goal is to perserve as much juice as you can. One trick is to make the initial cut on a divet to bleed less. Subsequent cuts can be made in a bowl if you’re mad skilled and not liable to cut yourself. If you’re a clutz like me, just try and cut with the round side facing down and flat side upwards. Immediately throw pieces into a bowl to catch as much of the juice as you can.</li>
  <li>Heat oil In pan and add any optional fragrants such as scallions.</li>
  <li>Stir fry the tomatoes in a wok until you have a layer of juice on the wok and the tomatoes are no longer stiff.</li>
  <li>Once enough liquid has accumulated, add the whisked eggs. Because there is no butter/little oil, you will need to scrape the eggs off the bottom of the wok occasionally.</li>
  <li>Once there appears to be no more runny eggs, add sugar, chili flakes and ketchup to taste and stir.</li>
  <li>Garnish with additional scallions if you want.</li>
</ol>

<p>More notes:</p>
<ul>
  <li>What I love most about this recipe is that it is super easy to make it to your tastes. You can easily taste the tomato juice throughout and alter to make it spicy, sweet, or salty. A two to one sugar to salt ratio seems good to me but I know I generally run sweet over salty.</li>
  <li>Same with mouthfeel: you can make mushier tomatoes, big tomatoes, etc. based on how you cut it.</li>
  <li>Other cultures have their own version of this dish. If your mouth isn’t feeling particularly Asian, spices such as Thyme, Dill, or latin-y hot sauce go well with eggs and tomatoes.</li>
  <li>Basically throw anything on this and it’ll probably be fine. i.e. you can stirfry garlic, ginger, chili peppers, or scallions before or garnish at the end.</li>
  <li>Generally 1-2 more eggs than you any amount of tomatoes you choose is a good rule of thumb, as long as your tomatoes aren’t enormous.</li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Fermented Black Bean Pumpkin (豆豉南瓜？)</title>
	  <link>//fermented-black-bean-pumpkin</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2019-10-15T06:18:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fermented-black-bean-pumpkin</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This is probably my favorite recipe to make, in part because it was the first thing I learned from my original sifu. Also in part because this is the one recipe that, when I cook it for other people, they are actually like “oh this was not bad.”</p>

<p>It doesn’t hurt I have a mad sweet tooth and kabucha is even sweeter than butternut squash. People say it’s like half pumkin, half sweet potato. Anyway, Kabocha is a Japanese pumpkin that is probably best in the fall but like most squashes lasts through the winter.</p>

<p>I like to make it mushy by the end because you get extra flavorful mush at the bottom. Plus, it’s better if you’re cooking for elderly, very young, or sick people who need to eat mushy foods. If you like more solid chunks, though just reduce the water. It definitely looks better this way.</p>

<p>This goes for basically everything I make: the spice ratio is pretty unscientific. I proobably tend towards more fragrants/natural flavor and less salt than some people.  Worst case scenario, you get to the end and think it isn’t salty enough and you can add more soy sauce.</p>

<p>Ingredients:</p>
<ul>
  <li>4 tablespoons douchi black beans (豆豉）</li>
  <li>3 cloves garlic</li>
  <li>1 Kabocha pumpkin </li>
  <li>Cooking Oil </li>
  <li>1.5 tablespoon Soy sauce </li>
  <li>1 tablespoon chili pepper flakes (optional)</li>
  <li>Half bowl of water (~3 cups)</li>
</ul>

<p>Directions </p>
<ol>
  <li>Rinse black beans in tap water.</li>
  <li>Add enough water to barely cover black beans and soak for around 10-20 minutes </li>
  <li>Smash and mince the 4 cloves of garlic </li>
  <li>Mix the garlic with the black beans and tablespoon of chili pepper flakes </li>
  <li>Cut the pumpkin into 1 inch cubes:
    <ul>
      <li>Cut in half once</li>
      <li>Take out seeds but try to leave as much pulp as you can </li>
      <li>Cut into fourths  </li>
      <li>Cut off the corners so you can lay the pumpkin flat - see picture.</li>
      <li>cut length wise at angle from center into ~3 strips</li>
      <li>Cut width-wise into 1in cubes 
<img src="assets/images/adrian-cutting.jpg" alt="Cutting corners" /></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>In large wok, add oil and on high heat</li>
  <li>Put in garlic mixture once hot </li>
  <li>Stirfry until fragrant </li>
  <li>Add pumpkin until sides of pumpkins get golden brown </li>
  <li>Add water to cover the pumpkin.</li>
  <li>Add soy sauce</li>
  <li>Continue heating at high flame until it boils then turn to med low heat to simmer. Mix every 5-10 minutes. </li>
  <li>Continue simmering (30min-1hour) until pumpkin is tender and sauce has reduced</li>
  <li>Add more soy sauce to taste. </li>
</ol>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
