<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>tlebryk.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>A smorgasbord of psuedo-scientific observations about Hong Kong, clickbate headlines, and the thing the internet most needs: another food blog.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Fermented Black Bean Pumpkin</title>
	  <link>//fermented-black-bean-pumpkin</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2019-10-15T06:18:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fermented-black-bean-pumpkin</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This is probably my favorite recipe to make, in part because it was the first thing I learned from my original sifu. Also in part because this is the one recipe that, when I cook it for other people, they are actually like “oh this was not bad.”</p>

<p>It doesn’t hurt I have a mad sweet tooth and kabucha is even sweeter than butternut squash. People say it’s like half pumkin, half sweet potato. Anyway, Kabocha is a Japanese pumpkin that is probably best in the fall but like most squashes lasts through the winter.</p>

<p>I like to make it mushy by the end because you get extra flavorful mush at the bottom. Plus, it’s better if you’re cooking for elderly, very young, or sick people who need to eat mushy foods. If you like more solid chunks, though just reduce the water. It definitely looks better this way.</p>

<p>This goes for basically everything I make: the spice ratio is pretty unscientific. I proobably tend towards more fragrants/natural flavor and less salt than some people.  Worst case scenario, you get to the end and think it isn’t salty enough and you can add more soy sauce.</p>

<p>Ingredients:</p>
<ul>
  <li>4 tablespoons douchi black bean paste (豆豉）</li>
  <li>3 cloves garlic</li>
  <li>1 Kabocha pumpkin </li>
  <li>Cooking Oil </li>
  <li>1.5 tablespoon Soy sauce </li>
  <li>1 tablespoon chili pepper flakes (optional)</li>
  <li>Half bowl of water (~3 cups)</li>
</ul>

<p>Directions </p>
<ol>
  <li>Rinse black beans in tap water.</li>
  <li>Add enough water to barely cover black beans and soak for around 10-20 minutes </li>
  <li>Smash and mince the 4 cloves of garlic </li>
  <li>Mix the garlic with the black beans and tablespoon of chili pepper flakes </li>
  <li>Cut the pumpkin into 1 inch cubes:
    <ul>
      <li>Cut in half once</li>
      <li>Take out seeds but try to leave as much pulp as you can </li>
      <li>Cut into fourths  </li>
      <li>Cut off the corners so you can lay the pumpkin flat - see picture.</li>
      <li>cut length wise at angle from center into ~3 strips</li>
      <li>Cut width-wise into 1in cubes 
<img src="assets/images/adrian-cutting.jpg" alt="Cutting corners" /></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>In large wok, add oil and on high heat</li>
  <li>Put in garlic mixture once hot </li>
  <li>Stirfry until fragrant </li>
  <li>Add pumpkin until sides of pumpkins get golden brown </li>
  <li>Add water to cover the pumpkin.</li>
  <li>Add soy sauce</li>
  <li>Continue heating at high flame until it boils then turn to med low heat to simmer. Mix every 5-10 minutes. </li>
  <li>Continue simmering (30min-1hour) until pumpkin is tender and sauce has reduced</li>
  <li>Add more soy sauce to taste. </li>
</ol>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
