<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo in Hong Kong and Stuff - Articles</title>
    <description>A smorgasbord of psuedo-scientific observations about Hong Kong, clickbate headlines, and the thing the internet most needs: another food blog.</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Tomato Egg Stirfry (番茄炒蛋)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are tons of versions of this classic Hong Kong comfort food but every one I’ve found does this recipe the proper way. That is: scramble the eggs, remove, stir fry tomatoes, and then add eggs back in at the end.
No one (by that I mean sample size of four Hong Kongers I cook with) actually cares enough to go through the work of scrambling first then cleaning the pan.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 05:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Tomato-Egg-Stirfry</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Tomato-Egg-Stirfry</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Fermented Black Bean Pumpkin (豆豉南瓜？)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is probably my favorite recipe to make, in part because it was the first thing I learned from my original sifu. Also in part because this is the one recipe that, when I cook it for other people, they are actually like “oh this was not bad.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 06:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/fermented-black-bean-pumpkin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/fermented-black-bean-pumpkin</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>What People are Saying about the Protests Part I</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first part in an ongoing series of posts excerpting different perspectives I encounter on the protests in Hong Kong. This is in no way a representative sample of Hong Kong, nor should these people be thought to speak for everyone in their demographic. However, hopefully this gives some color, and alternative perspectives, to what the media is publishing about the protests.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 06:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/what-people-are-saying-about-the-protests-part-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-people-are-saying-about-the-protests-part-1</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Housing Placeholder</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A placeholder for housing related stuff going on in my life.
&lt;!-- /wp:quote --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 06:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/housing-placeholder</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/housing-placeholder</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
